[
    {
        "Question": "A 45 year old woman is investigated after two episodes of renal colic. A plain abdominal Xray reveals small opacities in both kidneys. No abnormalities are found on physical examination. Biochemical investigation show\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Findings | Normal |\n| Adjusted calcium | 2.85 | 2.15-2.55 |\n| Phosphate | 0.7 | 0.6-1.25 |\n| Alkaline phosphatase | 0.95 | 20-120 |\n| Creatinine | 72 | 5-110 |\n| PTH | 2.7 | 0.95-5.7 |",
        "Option 1": "Primary hyperparathyroidism",
        "Option 2": "Primary hypoparathyroidism",
        "Option 3": "Pseudo hyperparathyroidism",
        "Option 4": "Secondary hyperparathyroidism",
        "Option 5": "Tertiary\thyperparathyroidism",
        "Correct Answer": "Primary hyperparathyroidism"
    },
    {
        "Question": "a 69 year old man has been admitted to the high dependency unit following an anterior resection under general anesthesia. He was given 2 mg of intra-thecal morphine. On examination, he looks pale and drowsy. ABG results are\nWhich of the following is the most likely diagnosis?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | PH | Pco2 | Po2 | Base excess | Glucose | Lactate |\n| Findings | 7.28 | 8.1 | 10.2 | 2.1 | 21 | 4 |\n| Normal | 7.35 - 7.45 | 4.7 - 6 | 11.9 - 13.3 | -2 to +2 | 4-7 | .5 - 2.2 |",
        "Option 1": "Diabetic ketoacidosis",
        "Option 2": "Metabolic acidosis",
        "Option 3": "Metabolic alkalosis",
        "Option 4": "Respiratory acidosis",
        "Option 5": "Respiratory alkalosis",
        "Correct Answer": "Respiratory acidosis"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 72 year old man with a body mass index of 18.4 has not eaten for four days following the removal of an adenocarcinoma from his descending colon. His urea is found to be 12 mmol (n = 3.2 – 7.5) and creatinine is 346 umol/L (n = 35-110) , abg is ordered, the most likely set of results would be:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Ph | pO2 | Pco2 | Bicarbonate |\n| A | 7.23 | 13.6 | 3.8 | 13.5 |\n| B | 7.30 | 8.8 | 8.3 | 30.5 |\n| C | 7.36 | 11.5 | 5.3 | 30.5 |\n| D | 7.43 | 16.4 | 3.7 | 21 |\n| E | 7.49 | 12.6 | 3.9 | 24 |\n| Normal | 7.35-7.45 | 11.9-13.3 | 4.7-6 | 22-26 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 65 year old man is admitted with a two week history of projectile vomiting. Investigations are done and confirm a benign pyloric stenosis. What is the expected result?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | K | Na | Bicarbonate |\n| A | 2.6 | 148 | 36 |\n| B | 3.4 | 156 | 24 |\n| C | 3.2 | 118 | 36 |\n| D | 6.0 | 120 | 15 |\n| E | 2.8 | 128 | 14 |\n| Normal | 3.5-4.9 | 137-144 | 22-26 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 42 year old man undergone a small bowel resection for chron’s disease. Four days postoperatively he develops a high output intestinal fistula. Investigations reveal the fistula originated from a small bowel anastomosis situated in the upper ilium. Fistula losses amount to 1800 ml/24 hours. What is the expected acid base balance?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | K | Na | Bicarbonate |\n| A | 2.6 | 148 | 36 |\n| B | 3.4 | 156 | 24 |\n| C | 3.2 | 118 | 36 |\n| D | 6.0 | 120 | 15 |\n| E | 2.8 | 128 | 14 |\n| Normal | 3.5-4.9 | 137-144 | 22-26 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "E"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 40 year old man is admitted to the emergency department having collapsed. On examination, the abdomen is soft and there are no signs of peritonitis. Pigmentation of mucus membranes of the mouth is noted, investigations reveal hypotension (80/60) sinus rhythm , a normal chest Xray and abdominal ultrasound. Her only previous history is unexplained anemia and thyroxin relplaceement therapy for an immune thyroiditis. What is the expected result?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | K | Na | Bicarbonate |\n| A | 2.6 | 148 | 36 |\n| B | 3.4 | 156 | 24 |\n| C | 3.2 | 118 | 36 |\n| D | 6.0 | 120 | 15 |\n| E | 2.8 | 128 | 14 |\n| Normal | 3.5-4.9 | 137-144 | 22-26 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 72 year-old-woman , who was treated for breast cancer 20 years ago, presents with tiredness. Constipation back and chest pain. On examination , reveals localized tendeness over thoracic vertebrae and anterior ribs. Her pulse is 110 and BP is 90/60 an ECG shows shortened QT interval , her biochemistery results are:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| Sodium | 137 | 135-145 |\n| Potassium | 4.3 | 3.5-5.5 |\n| Corrected calcium | 3.8 | 2.2-2.6 |\n| Phosphate | 0.8 | 0.8-14 |\nChest xray shows lytic lesions in the left anterior third rib , which of the following treatments should be administered first?",
        "Option 1": "0.9 % sodium chloride",
        "Option 2": "Calcitonin",
        "Option 3": "Cinacalcet",
        "Option 4": "Pamidronate",
        "Option 5": "Prednisolone",
        "Correct Answer": "0.9 % sodium chloride"
    },
    {
        "Question": "24 year old with BMI is 13.5 is referred to be investigated for malabsorption. On investigation, his serum potassium is 2.5 mmol/L and serum bicarbonate is 46 mmol/L, which of the following serum electrolyte would confirm vomiting as a cause of metabolic alkalosis?\n\nTable Data:\n|  |  | Finding | Normal |\n| A | Calcium | 1.6 | 2.15-2.55 |\n| B | Chloride | 89 | 95-107 |\n| C | Creatinine | 140 | 35-110 |\n| D | Magnesium | 4 | .75-1.05 |\n| E | Sodium | 133 | 137-144 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 62 year old woman has persistent left calf pain after catheter embolycetomy after acutely ischemic limb. Her pulse was 100, BP = 110/60 , UOP = 10 ml in the last hour and appeared brown red in color. Doppler ultrasound of left leg shows normal postoperative blood flow and no evidence of thrombosis. Blood results show:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| Hemoglobin | 130 | 135-175 |\n| Sodium | 137 | 137-144 |\n| Potassium | 7.1 | 3.5-5 |\n| Urea | 285 | 35-1110 |\n| CK | 12000 | 25-195 |\n Administration with which of the following drug would be most appropriate?",
        "Option 1": "IV fluid",
        "Option 2": "Spironolactone",
        "Option 3": "Glucose",
        "Option 4": "Furasamide",
        "Option 5": "IV ca gluconate",
        "Correct Answer": "IV ca gluconate"
    },
    {
        "Question": "a 73 year old man during preoperative check, he is found to have:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Potassium | Urea | Creatinine | GFR |\n| Finding | 6.2 | 5.6 | 74 | 74 |\n| Normal | 3.5 - 5 | 3.2 - 7.5 | >90 | >90 | \n The abnormality is inhibition of Na/K pump in the collecting duct. Which of the following is responsible for that?",
        "Option 1": "Furosemide",
        "Option 2": "Thiazide",
        "Option 3": "Mannitol",
        "Option 4": "Spironolactone",
        "Option 5": "Bumetanide",
        "Correct Answer": "Spironolactone"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A patient presented to the emergency department after collapse, her blood investigations revealed the following results:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Na | PH | Ca |\n| Values | 119 | 7.34 | 2.2 |\n| Normal ranges | 135-145 | 7.35-7.45 | 2.2-2.6 |\nShe has been on furesmide for her cardiac failure and was thought to be responsible for these abnormalities. What is the site of action of furosemide?",
        "Option 1": "Proximal convoluted tubules",
        "Option 2": "Distal convoluted tubules",
        "Option 3": "Ascending limb of loop of Henle",
        "Option 4": "Collecting duct",
        "Option 5": "Descending limp of loop of Henle",
        "Correct Answer": "Ascending limb of loop of Henle"
    },
    {
        "Question": "** A 62 years old female presented with spontaneous fractures on minimal trauma. Her laboratory investigations would probably show:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Alkaline phosphatase | Calcium | Phosphorus |\n| A | Increased | Normal | Normal |\n| B | Decreased | Increased | Increased |\n| C | Normal | Normal | Normal |\n| D | Increased | Increased | Increased |\n| E | Decreased | Decreased | Decreased |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 24 year old man falls off his motorbike, fracturing one arm, both femurs and rupturing his spleen. He required surgery and 20 units of blood. Twenty-four hours after admission he has passed 350 ml of urine. His blood pressure is 90/50 mmHg and he has low skin turgor. Which of the following best describes the changes in the renin-angiotensin system initated at the juxtaglomerular apparatus in the patient?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Renin concentration | Angiotensin II concentration | Aldosterone concentration |\n| A | Low | Low | Low |\n| B | Low | High | Low |\n| C | High | Low | Low |\n| D | High | Low | High |\n| E | High | High | High |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "E"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 24 year old man falls off his motorbike, fracturing one arm, both femurs and rupturing his spleen. He required surgery and 20 units of blood. Twenty-four hours after admission he has passed 350 ml of urine. His blood pressure is 90/50 mmHg and he has low skin turgor. Biochemistry results as follows:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| Serum potassium | 5.6 | 3.5-5 |\n| Serum urea | 21 | 3.2-7 |\n| Serum creatinine | 140 | 35-110 |\n| Urine sodium | 5 | 15-200 |\n| Urine urea | 480 | 450-500 |\nWhich of the following best describes kidney response to attempt to maintain renal function in this man?",
        "Option 1": "Decreasing efferent arteriolar diameter",
        "Option 2": "Decreasing glomerular permeability",
        "Option 3": "Increase active urea secretion",
        "Option 4": "Decrease afferent arteriolar diameter",
        "Option 5": "Increase glomerular permeability",
        "Correct Answer": "Decreasing efferent arteriolar diameter"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 24 year old man falls off his motorbike, fracturing one arm, both femurs and rupturing his spleen. He required surgery and 20 units of blood. Twenty-four hours after admission he has passed 350 ml of urine. His blood pressure is 90/50 mmHg and he has low skin turgor. Biochemistry results as follows:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| Serum potassium | 5.6 | 3.5-5 |\n| Serum urea | 21 | 3.2-7 |\n| Serum creatinine | 140 | 35-110 |\n| Urine sodium | 5 | 15-200 |\n| Urine urea | 480 | 450-500 |",
        "Option 1": "Hypoaldosteronism due to adrenal trauma",
        "Option 2": "Obstructed glomeruli due to intravascular hemolysis",
        "Option 3": "Renal vasoconstriction due to hypovolemia",
        "Option 4": "Tubular necrosis due to hypoxia",
        "Option 5": "Arterial compression due to retroperitoneal hematoma",
        "Correct Answer": "Renal vasoconstriction due to hypovolemia"
    },
    {
        "Question": "45 year old patient diagnosed having insulinoma . which lab findings will appear in his blood?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Insulin | C peptide |\n| A | High | Low |\n| B | Low | High |\n| C | Lwo | Low |\n| D | High | High |\n| E | Normal | Normal |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 55 years old woman presents to her GP with an enlarged thyroid gland and a 4 months history of feeling tired, investigations revealed:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| TSH | 12 | 0.4-4.3 |\n| Free T4 | 10 | 9-26 |\nWhich of the following is most likely cause?",
        "Option 1": "Primary hyperthyroidism",
        "Option 2": "Primary hypothyroidism",
        "Option 3": "secondary hypothyroidism",
        "Option 4": "secondary hyperthyroidism",
        "Option 5": "sick euthyroid",
        "Correct Answer": "Primary hypothyroidism"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 48 year-old woman presents with history of anorexia, followed by nausea ,vomiting and abdominal pain. Her pulse is 130 beat/minute and blood pressure is 85/50 mmHg blood tests show:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Na | K | Ca | Glucose |\n| Finding | 120 | 6.6 | 2.2 | 3.9 |\n| Normal | 135-145 | 3.5-5 | 2.15-2.55 | 4-6 |\n\nA CT scan of her abdomen does not demonstrate any gastrointestinal pathology, analysis of which of the following hormones is most likely to be helpful in establishing the diagnosis?",
        "Option 1": "ACTH",
        "Option 2": "ADH",
        "Option 3": "GH",
        "Option 4": "PTH",
        "Option 5": "TSH",
        "Correct Answer": "ACTH"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 21 year old man has been hit by a cricket ball on the side of the head. Initially he has a GCS (E4, V5,M4) his left pupil dilates, and he begins to demonstrate extensor posturing of the limbs. What are the most likely changes to his vital signs since injury?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Blood pressure | Heart rate |\n| A | Decreased | Decreases |\n| B | Decreased | Increased |\n| C | Decreased | Normal |\n| D | Increased | Decreased |\n| E | Increased | Increased |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "Question": "50 year old man presented by malignant brain tumor (glioblastoma) in the right thalamus. Despite the treatment, the manifestation progress up to cushing triad appears. Which of these are the manifestations?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Respiratory rate | Blood pressure | Pulse |\n| A | Decrease | Decrease | Increase |\n| B | Decrease | Increase | Increases |\n| C | Decreases | Increase | Decrease |\n| D | Increase | Decrease | Decrease |\n| E | Increase | Increase | Decrease |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 19 year old man is attacked outside a club and beaten with a basketball bat. He sustained a blow to the right side of his head. He is brought to the emergency room and a policy of observation is adopted. His GCS deteriorated and he becomes comatose. Which of the following parameters is most likely to be present?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Baroreceptors | Vagal tone |\n| A | Increase | Decrease |\n| B | Increase | Increase |\n| C | Decrease | Decrease |\n| D | Increase | Normal |\n| E | Normal | Normal |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "Question": "90 years old is brought to emergency department. On examination he is shivering and feeling dizzy. The following is found:\n\nTable Data:\n| Heart rate | Cvp | Systemic vascular resistance | Cardiac output |\n| Increased | Decreased | Decreased | increased |",
        "Option 1": "Septic shock",
        "Option 2": "Neurogenic shock",
        "Option 3": "Cardiogenic shock",
        "Option 4": "Hemorrhagic shock",
        "Option 5": "None of the above",
        "Correct Answer": "Septic shock"
    },
    {
        "Question": "An 18 year old woman recently started the combines oral contraceptive pill and present with acute abdominal pain, vomiting and muscle weakenss on examination she has a pulse rate of 86 and BP = 160/85 , other findings are: \nTable Data:\n|  | Result | Normal |\n| Serum amylase | 110 | <100 |\n| Serum ALT | 22 | <50 |\n| Alkaline phosphatase | 102 | 50-120 |\n| Albumin | 41 | 35-50 |\n| Gamma GT | 37 | <60 |\n| Bilirubin | 10 | 0-20 |\n| Calcium | 2.41 | 2.2-2.7 |\n| Plasma glucose | 5 | 4.5-6 |\n| Triglycerides | 1.5 | <1.7 |\nWhat is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1": "Acute intermittent porphyria",
        "Option 2": "Diabetic ketoacidosis",
        "Option 3": "Hypoparathyroidism",
        "Option 4": "Mumps",
        "Option 5": "Pancreatitis",
        "Correct Answer": "Acute intermittent porphyria"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 58 year old man underwent an emergency appendectomy. Which of the following physiological parameters are consistent with sepsis?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Heart rate | Systemic vascular resistance | Cardiac output |\n| A | Decrease | Decrease | Increase |\n| B | Increase | Increase | Decrease |\n| C | Increase | Decrease | Increase |\n| D | Decrease | Increase | Decrease |\n| E | Increase | Decrease | Decrease |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Rugby player has injury at C5 and C6 spine vertebrae and he is now in ICU. What is finding do you expect to be found in his blood?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Capillary pressure | HR | Blood pressure | SVR |\n| A | Decrease | Decrease | Decrease | Decrease |\n| B | Decrease | Increase | Decrease | Increase |\n| C | Decrease | Increase | Decrease | Decrease |\n| D | Decrease | Decrease | Increase | Increase |\n| E | Decrease | Increase | Increase | Increase |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "Question": "40 year old man with history of smoking for long period, what is his ABG?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Co2 | Hco3 |\n| A | Normal | High |\n| B | High | Low |\n| C | High | High |\n| D | Low | High |\n| E | Low | normal |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "a 23 year old male sustained thoracic trauma and developed himisection of the cord. What he will show the following pattern of weakness below the level of the lesion?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Motor | Pain and temperature | Proprioception |\n| A | Ipsilateral | Contralateral | Ipsilateral |\n| B | Contralateral | Ipsilateral | Contralateral |\n| C | Contralateral | Ipsilateral | Ipsilateral |\n| D | Ipsilateral | Contralateral | Contralateral |\n| E | Ipsilateral | Ipsilateral | Ipsilateral |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 29 year old woman presents to the emergency department with thirst and polyuria. She does not smoke and has rash that resolved three months prior to her presentation. Her history is otherwises unremarkable. Her lung Xray shows hilar shadowing serum biochemistry is performed and reveals:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Finding | Normal |\n| Adjusted calcium | 3.45 | 2.15- 2.55 |\n| Phosphate | 1.2 | 0.6-1.25 |\n| Creatinine | 150 | 35-110 |\n| Alkaline phosphate | 85 | 20-120 | \n She was treated with normal saline and started on a course of hydrocortisone. A week later her corrected calcium is within normal range, but her parathyroid hormone is 0.4 (normal 1-6.5) which of the following is most likely to be the cause?",
        "Option 1": "Carcinoma of the lung",
        "Option 2": "Hypercalemic hypocalciuria",
        "Option 3": "Primary hyperparathyroidism",
        "Option 4": "Sarcoidosis",
        "Option 5": "Secondary hyperparathyroidism",
        "Correct Answer": "Sarcoidosis"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 33 year old lady presents with thyroid swelling and the pathology reveals medullary thyroid carcinoma which of the following parameter indicates for recurrence of this condition?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | TSH | Free T4 | Free T3 | Thyro globulin | Calcitonin |\n| A | 1.5 | 17.2 | 1.3 | 25 | <15 |\n| B | 1.2 | 15.6 | 1.4 | 25 | 2000 |\n| C | 18.5 | 8.2 | 0.8 | 20 | <15 |\n| D | <0.03 | 45.6 | 3.6 | 22 | <15 |\n| E | 0.1 | 3 | 4.3 | 200 | <15 |\n| Normal | 0.4-4.3 | 0.9-26 | 0.9-2.6 | <60 | <15 |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "Question": "man with history of hypertension is confused 24 hour after fracture femur. Preoperative medication was aspirin, codeine phosphate and flurothiazide. Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs is added for pain control and this biological labs are taken showing:\n\nTable Data:\n| Na | 128 | 137-144 |\n| K | 5.8 | 3.5 - 5 |\n| Urea | 38 | 3.2 - 7.5 |\n| Creatinine | 457 | 35 - 110 |\n| GFR | 12 | More than 90 | \n Which of these enzymes is affected?",
        "Option 1": "Catechol O methyl transferase",
        "Option 2": "Carbonic anhydrase",
        "Option 3": "Cyclooxygenase",
        "Option 4": "Monoamine oxidase",
        "Option 5": "Reductase",
        "Correct Answer": "Cyclooxygenase"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A previoushy healthy 32 years old man is admitted with fracture shaft of the femur following road traffic accident. 12 hours after admission his blood pressure is changed from 125/75 to 75/50 and pulse from 75 beats/ minute to 120 beats / minute. on examination he has central cyanosis and tachypnea and ECG show T wave inversion from VI to V4 and his ABG:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | PH | PCO2 | PO2 |\n| Finding | 7.46 | 8 | 3.5 |\n| Normal | 7.35-7.45 | 11.9-13.3 | 4.7-6 |\nWhat is the most likely cause?",
        "Option 1": "Cardiac tamponade",
        "Option 2": "Fat embolism",
        "Option 3": "Hypovolemia",
        "Option 4": "Myocardial infarction",
        "Option 5": "Pulmonary thromboembolism",
        "Correct Answer": "Fat embolism"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A 24-year-old man was involved in a road traffic collision six days ago. He sustained an abdominal injury requiring splenectomy and bilateral femoral fractures condition is stable but he continues to ooze from his femoral Incisions and develops a petechial rash In his extremities. current blood results show:\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Findings | Normal |\n| Hemoglobin | 78 | 135-175 |\n| Mean corpuscular volume | 100 | 80-96 |\n| White cell count | 11.9 *10^9 | 4-11 |\n| Platelets | 34 * 10^9 | 150-400 |\n| Prothrombin time | 18 | 11.5-15.5 |\n| APTT | 60 | 30-40 |\n| Fibrinogen | 0.7 | 1.8-5.4 |\nWhat is the likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1": "DIC",
        "Option 2": "Fat embolism",
        "Option 3": "Heparin therapy",
        "Option 4": "Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura",
        "Option 5": "Resuscitation-associated coagulopathy",
        "Correct Answer": "DIC"
    },
    {
        "Question": "A patient with Extradural Hematoma Presented to the emergency department if having hypertension and increased intracranial pressure. What of the following are the Components of the Cushing reflex/triad?\n\nTable Data:\n|  | Blood pressure | Heart rate |\n| A | Decreased | Decreased |\n| B | Decreased | Increased |\n| C | Decreased | Normal |\n| D | Increased | Decreased |\n| E | Increased | Increased |",
        "Option 1": "A",
        "Option 2": "B",
        "Option 3": "C",
        "Option 4": "D",
        "Option 5": "E",
        "Correct Answer": "D"
    }
]